Yamantaka Mandala, 1991.
A mandala is a visual
representation of the sacred
Buddhist universe, which
is used in meditation
and initiation rites.
The creation of a mandala
is believed to benefit all
beings, and the time and space
it requires is consecrated
through prayer, ritual
music, and performance.
A team of monks-in-residence
created this colored sand
mandala at the museum in 1991
over a period of four weeks.
While sand mandalas are
intended to be ephemeral,
the MIA preserved it in order
to honor the 1.2 million
Tibetans who lost their
lives to political-religious
persecution during
the 20th century.
The museum thanks the Tibetan
American Foundation of
Minnesota for bringing the
Gyuto monks to Minnesota and
for their efforts to preserve
Tibetan cultural traditions.