Prestige Stool, (Kuo
fo). Did you know?
The beads on this stool
were sewn on by hand.
Look underneath the
stool, however, and you
can see commercially
made printed fabric.
Bead-covered wooden stools and
thrones are one of the most
prevalent art forms among
the various kingdoms and
chiefdoms in the Cameroon
grassfields region.
This example, once part of
the royal treasury, belongs in
the category of travel stools,
usually used in conjunction
with more private,
minor ceremonies and
rituals at the palace.
The leopard imagery confirms
the object's royal status.
It alludes to the belief that
the king could temporarily
transform himself into
this feared predator.