Celestial Horse, 25-220 CE.
Chinese government envoys sent
to Central Asia returned to
court marveling over a breed
of heavenly horse like no
other, a stout animal with
powerful back and shoulders
that worked so hard
it sweated blood.
The Chinese Emperor Wu, (r.
141-87 BCE), became obsessed
with these stories and
dispatched diplomats and
later a military force
to obtain the horses.
His interest in these
remarkable horses and the
growing role horses played
in military campaigns largely
account for the popularity
of the horse and art from the
Han dynasty, in particular
the era in which Wu ruled.
Bronze horses such as this
one were placed in elaborately
furnished aristocratic tombs
and were meant to provide
transportation for the
deceased in the afterlife.
This spirited horse, a blend
of ideal and real in its
modeling, captures the spirit
of the fabled celestial
horses of the Han dynasty.