Bowl depicting ladies on
horseback c.1180-1220.
These bowls date from the
Seljuq period in Iran,
around 1100 or 1200.
The Seljuqs were familial
clans who invaded Iran
from the Asian steppe.
Although not Muslim, the
Seljuqs quickly assimilated
to the Islamic culture of
their conquered peoples.
Under the Seljuqs, the
centers of power shifted from
Baghdad in Iraq to what is
modern-day Turkey and Iran.
These bowls illustrate
the silhouette effect
popular in Seljuk art.
Decoration is applied directly
to the pot, painted in a
black slip and covered with
a clear or colored glaze.
This technique allows the
human figures to stand
out against either a busy
or a blank background.
These scenes and other figural
designs were often taken
from Iranian epic hero poems.
Another important feature
of these bowls is the
Arabic script that
adorns the outer rim.