Scenes in and around
Kyoto, early 17th century.
This screen shows a bird's-eye
view of the city of Kyoto,
the capital of Japan for
most of its early history.
Many famous sites of
Kyoto are pictured.
To orient yourself, look
for the river that emerges
in the middle of the
far right panel and then
flows to the upper left.
This is the Kamo River,
which flows north-south
and bisects the city.
It is crossed by several
bridges - the Fifth Avenue
Bridge, visible in the second
panel from the right, and the
Third Avenue Bridge, in the
upper part of the fourth
panel from the right.
At the very top of the second
and third panels from the
right is the famous Buddhist
temple Kiyomizudera,
with its long staircase
and high veranda.
A group of people gather
there to admire blooming
cherry trees below.
At the far upper left of the
screen, look for Kamigamo
Shrine near which an annual
horse race is taking place.