Avalokiteshvara Bodhisattva
in the Watermoon Form, Shuiyue
Guanyin, 12th century. Of the
many manifestations of the
Bodhisattva Avalokiteshvara,
perhaps none was more
prevalent in East Asia
than the uniquely Chinese
form known as Watermoon
Avalokiteshvara, which
later also spread
to Korea and Japan.
This form of the Bodhisattva
presides over his own
paradise, Patalaka, which
is described in scripture as
a rugged seaside cave from
which Avalokiteshvara could
admire the reflection of
the moon in the water.
Appropriately, he appears
meditative and relaxed and
is seated informally in
the royal-ease posture.
Ornately dressed, with silk
robes, fluttering sashes,
jewelry, and an elaborate
hairstyle, he also wears a
headpiece that features an
image of AmitÄbha, the Buddha
to whom Avalokiteshvara
attends.
Believers might look to a
sculpture like this as a
guide for their own journeys
toward enlightenment.