Ceremonial Vessel in the Form
of a Water Buffalo, 1000-300
BCE. Among the first
domesticated animals in
Thailand, the water buffalo
was instrumental to the
plowing of rice fields and
also a likely symbol of
abundance for the afterlife.
These three vessels, including
an exceptionally large one in
the form of a water buffalo,
were found as a group in
graves, where they had been
smashed as offerings over
the bodies of the deceased.
Now reconstructed, they
present important developments
from the earlier ceramics
seen at left, with their
use of multiple colors on
a single vessel, incised
and rope-marked patterns
for surface texture, and
inventive forms gracefully
standing on several feet.