Vase, 18th century.
This base derives from
the bronze Hu vessel,
but is made in cloisonné.
The cloisonné technique
reached China from Byzantium,
present-day Istanbul, between
1200 and 1400 CE, but Chinese
artisans made it their own.
The general stylistic
trend was toward bigger,
more complicated, and
luxurious creations.
During the Qing Dynasty
reigns of Emperors Kangxi,
(r. 1662-1722), and Qianlong,
(r. 1736-95), cloisonné
was perfected and reached
its artistic summit.
Colors were more delicate,
and filigrees more
flexible and fluent.
Previously used for religious
paraphernalia, cloisonné now
embellished secular objects.
This vase is a typical
product of the 1700s.
Supported on a straight-foot
ring, the globular body
rises to a long, cylindrical
neck and terminates
in a lipped rim.
The vase is decorated.