Hu Wine Vessel,
5th century BCE.
This storage vessel is
one of an important group
of hunting-scene hu.
They show the influence
of the nomadic art of
China's northern frontier.
The four major bands depict
men hunting birds, deer,
boars, and tigers, with
spears, knives, and bows.
Panels on the vessel's
shoulders show an
archer shooting from
the back of a four-horse
chariot with driver.
These pictorial scenes of
human activity represent
a revolutionary
departure in bronze art.
Previously, during the Shang
and Zhou periods, sacred
symbols and stylized animals
were formally arranged
with regard to hierarchy
and strict symmetry.
The subject here appears
secular rather than religious.