Saint Martin and the
Beggar, circa 1375-85.
This newly discovered panel
painting was a compartment
of a larger Spanish
Gothic altarpiece.
It was made in the flourishing
workshop of the brothers Jaume
and Pere Serra, in Barcelona.
It represents Saint
Martin, Bishop of Tours,
c. 315-397, who as a young
man had served in the
Roman army in Gaul.
One cold winter night, he came
upon a man bare and shivering,
and he cut his cloak
in half, to share it.
After this act of charity,
Christ appeared to Martin in
a dream, wearing the cloak,
and said, "What thou hast
done for that poor man,
thou hast done for me."
The painting's monumental
scale, refined coloring, and
expressive figures reflect the
influence of Italian painting,
particularly Sienese painting,
of which a number of examples
are displayed nearby.