Mo'ai Kavakava, 19th century.
A Mo'ai Kavakava is a small
wooden figure of a style
originated by the Rapa Nui
culture of Easter Island.
Each figure resembles
a standing, slightly
stooped, male human
with an emaciated body.
The name Mo'ai Kavakava is
formed from Moai for the
monumental monolithic human
figures found on Easter
Island and the word
Kavakava meaning ribs.
Little is known about the
cultural context of these
figures although they are
generally considered to be
representations of starving
ancestors or demons.
19th-century travelers
reported that these figures
were worn hanging around
the necks of men who took
part in the ritual dances
during public ceremonies.