Garniture set, one clock
and two vases, circa 1736.
Did you know?
A set of vases and clock,
connected visually by the use
of the same materials, often
adorned a mantlepiece or
the top of a large piece of
furniture, such as a commode
or console, within a room.
The fascination with Chinese
porcelain among aristocratic
circles increased during
the reign of Louis XV.
In reaction to the perceived
excesses of elaborate
naturalistic ornament of
the 1750s, mount makers
increasingly turned to
neoclassical designs, known
as Goût Grec, Greek taste,
in the 1760s and 1770s.
These beautifully chased
gilt-bronze mounts feature
classical Greco-Roman
motifs such as lion masks,
acanthus, and laurel
leaves, and pilasters.