Brook in Winter, 1914
E. Ambrose Webster was
thrilled by the effects of
light and was an attentive
observer of nature.
He was an influential teacher
and spent a great deal of time
as part of the Provincetown
art colony, working in the
open air among other artists
and younger students.
He was considered a leading
modernist in American during
the 1910s and exhibited in the
Armory Show, a massive 1913
exhibition that introduced
modern European artists to
Americans in a large number.
Brook in Winter shows
Webster's careful
observation of sunset
effects on a winter day.
He added slashes of purple
and searing orange through
the trees to give the feeling
of the long rays of the
sun transformed through
the brittle forest.